한글자막 제작 : 헉헉퍽퍽
의,오역 많음. 수정 재배포 자유
앤드류, 그거 알아?
Andrew, you know what?
우리가 부부였을때
당신은 내 성공을 원망했었어
You resented my success
when we were married, okay?
하지만 이제 당신 의견은
좆도 아니야
But now it is
absolutely eating you raw.
그분을 만나고서 가장 잘하신 건
그분과 헤어지신거죠
You were the best thing to ever
happen to him and he threw it away.
그래, 널 만나고서
네가 가장..
Yeah, you were the best thing--
I was the best thing
내가 가장 잘 한 일은
널 차버린거지
that ever happened to you
and you just threw it away.
부통령님, 회의에서 켄트 만나려면
지금 출발해야 합니다
Ma'am, we have to go now if you want
to catch Kent for a hostages meeting.
좋아, 들어봐
난 네가
Okay, listen,
I will not have you
나와 캐서린을 방해하게
놔두지 않을꺼야
undermine me with Catherine.
- 클러치백으로 할까요?
- 그래 좋아
- Will you be wanting a clutch?
- I will.
- 알겠습니다
- 아니 싫어
- Okay.
- I will not.
- 싫으세요?
- 아니아니 좋아. 그 가방으로 해
- Oh, you don't?
- No, no, I will. I want the bag.
아니, 난 캐서린이 나랑
추수감사절을 같이 보냈으면 한다고
No, I want Catherine
to spend Thanksgiving with me,
남자친구 놈팽이랑 말고
not some random boyfriend.
그리고 불쌍한 노인네는 어떻구
3월에 돌아가실지도 모른다는데?
And what about poor Memaw, who's
guaranteed to be dead by March?
운이 없다면 말야
With any luck.
그래, 축하해
Well, congratulations.
캐서린 조종법을
성공적으로 배우셨구만
You have successfully learned
how to manipulate Catherine.
그건 애를 모욕하는거야
How is that insulting to her?
젠장, 전방위로 빡돌게하네..
그래
God, you just turn it
all around-- okay.
- 끊어버리던가 해야지
- 출발할까요?
- Just hanging up on him.
- Shall we go?
- 그래, 어서 나가자
- 가방에 진통제 넣었어요
- Yeah, let's just get out.
- There's some Advil in the bag.
그래, 살인청부업자 번호도
넣어놨으면 좋겠네
Yeah, I hope we have a number
for a contract killer, too.
찾아볼께요
I'll do it.
바퀴 멋지네요, 마이크
새차에요?
Nice wheels, Mike.
This new?
아주 새건 아냐
네 엄마처럼
Not quite.
Like your mother,
이미 몇 놈들한테
돈과 사랑을 받았지
it's been previously loved and
paid for by a couple of guys.
빚 다 갚으셨나봐요?
I guess this means
you cleared your debts, huh?
아니, 빚에 더해놨지
No, I've added this to my debt.
"알콜중독 해결법 : 더 마셔라"
접근법
Oh, the old "drink your way
out of alcoholism" approach.
- 거 좋죠
- 아니, 이건 그때랑은 달라
- I like it.
- No, this isn't like when I drank.
술 문제 있었어요?
You had a drinking problem?
문제는 아니고
사건 정도
Not a problem.
Uh, an issue.
사건 정도도 아니지
약간의 장애
Not even an issue.
A hitch.
술 장애가 있었다고요?
You had a drinking hitch?
덴, 내 연봉이 10만 달러야
Dan, I owe 100 grand.
변화를 위해 할 수 있는게
아무것도 없어
Nothing I can do
will change that.
그래서 변화는 없다는걸
받아들였지
So, I've accepted
what I cannot change.
몇 만 달러 더 쓴다고
문제될껀 없어
A few extra grand
doesn't matter.
술마셨어요?
Are you drunk right now?
안녕하세요, 이건 씨
지방 신문은 읽어보셨나요?
Morning, Mr. Egan. Have you
read the regionality paper?
- 아뇨
- 네
- No.
- Okay.
좋은하루 되세요
Have a great day.
- 나만 보면 다들 저래요
- 아닌 것 같은데
- I get that all the time.
- No, you don't.
그런데 난 얘기해야 된다고
But I need to talk
저 자폐증걸린
마이클잭슨 같은 새끼랑
to that autistic lumberjack
son of a bitch.
오, 저기있네
안녕하세요 켄트
Oh, there he is.
Hi, Kent.
- 부통령님
- 요즘 필라테스 한다면서요?
- Madam Vice President.
- Hey, I heard you were doing Pilates.
당신한테 심장이 있는줄은 몰랐는데
I didn't know you had a core.
물론요
강철처럼 단단합니다
I do and it's like steel.
그래서 인질에 대해
아무것도
So are we really
not doing anything
안 해도 되나요?
about the hostages now?
- 정말 아무것도?
- 뭔가 하긴 할껍니다
- Nothing at all?
- We are doing something.
- 그래요? 뭘 하는데요?
- 아무것도요
- Yeah? What are we doing?
- Nothing.
수치들이 중재를 돕기 전까지는
Until the numbers
support intervention,
아무것도 하지 않는것이
우리가 할 수 있는 가장 긍정적인 행동입니다
doing nothing is the most
positive thing we can do.
말 한번 잘하시네요, 켄트
You know, it's just so great
talking to you, Kent.
전 게으름떠는거 좋아해요
I love being close
to the inaction.
오후에 있는 국제안보회의는
아직 유효하죠?
The national security meeting this
afternoon is still happening, right?
그럼요, 4시 30분에 인질과
SM-17D 미사일 방어 시스템
Yes, 4:30. Hostages and the SM-17
missile defense system sale
의 이스라엘 판매에 대해
토론이 있을 예정입니다
to Israel will both
be discussed.
SM-17d
소문자 d 말야
SM-17d.
There's a lower case D.
- 죄송합니다
- 디테일은 중요한거야
- Apologies, sir.
- Details are important.
- 소숫점 하나로 당뇨 환자는 죽을 수도 있다고
- 알겠습니다
- A misplaced decimal point
can kill a diabetic. - Yes, sir.
우리 거래가 어떻게 되느냐에 따라
회의 참석이 기다려지겠네
I look forward to attending
the meeting as per our deal.
대통령님은 부통령님의 참석을 좋아하십니다
물론 저도요
POTUS would love to have
you there, as would I.
만약 부통령님이
시간을 거스를 수 있다면 말이죠
That's if you can
possibly be back in time.
- 시간을 거슬러? 뭐가?
- 죄송합니다, 벌써 8시 45분이라
- Back in time from what?
- I'm sorry, I have an 8:45.
- 라이언 군
- 네, 알겠습니다
- Mr. Ryan.
- Yes, sir.
- 뭐가? 켄트?
- 부통령님
- What? Kent?
- Uh, ma'am.
- 응?
- 농촌 라디오를 들어보셨다면
- Yes?
- The Listen to Rural America program
중간선거 후에 부통령님이 대통령님과..
that you okayed with POTUS after
the midterms is looking--
러닝화로 갈아 신고
결승선에 있는
You know what? Why don't you
put on your running shoes
요점 좀 가져다 줄래, 조나?
and get to the fucking
point, Jonah?
노스캐롤라이나 돈육 협회에서
돼지잡이를 합니다
The North Carolina Pork Board
is having a pig picking today.
우아해 보이네
케이트 미들턴도 거기 온데?
Sounds classy. Will Kate
Middleton be there?
대통령님은 부통령님이
거기에 참석해서
POTUS would like
to get you down there
손 흔들며 "여어, 미국" 하시랍니다
and utilize your people skills
to kick off "U.S., Hey."
- 정말 그렇게 부른다고?
- 그렇습니다
- That's what they're gonna call it?
- Yeah.
누가 그런 개똥같은 이름을
생각해 낸거야?
Who came up with that
incredibly shitty name?
아마 제가 그랬습죠
That would be me, ma'am.
좋아, 내가 돼지 축제에 가서
Okay, so they want me
to go to a pig roast
불에 굽기도 전에
돌림으로 돼지랑
to meet a bunch of men
who probably took turns
떡쳐댄 놈들을 만났으면 하는거야?
to fuck the pig
before they roasted it?
돌림으로 했을것 같지는 않지만요
I wouldn't presume
they took turns.
너한테 말해두자면
난 4시 30분 회의에 참석할꺼야
Let me tell you something.
I'm going to that 4:30 meeting
수한테 시간을 되돌리라고 할꺼니까
even if I have to get Sue
to fly around the world
슈퍼맨처럼 자전하는 지구를
거꾸로 돌려서라도
the wrong way like Superman
and reverse time.
- 알아들었어?
- 네, 부통령님
- Do you understand that?
- Yes, ma'am.
좋아
Okay.
부통령님, 저희 아버지 상태가
더 안좋아지셨데요
Ma'am, my dad has taken
a turn for the worse.
제 생각에 돼지잡이도
좋지만..
I'm thinking this pig picking
is a good opportunity--
빠져, 빠져도 돼
아버지께 가봐
Oh, yeah, skip it.
Skip it. Go to him.
널 위해서 샌드위치와
발가락 6개 달린 남편감을 가져올께
I'll bring you back a sandwich
and a six-toed husband.
- 다른 공항에 착륙하신다면..
- 게리
- Maybe if she landed at a different base--
- Gary.
이건 네 전문분야가 아냐
This is not your area
of expertise.
그냥 달력에 타이핑하는거잖아
It's just typing
into a calendar.
미안 수
참 어려운 일이네
I'm sorry, Sue. Your job
is really difficult.
- 뭐라고?
- 넌 정말 효율적으로 일한다고
- Excuse me?
- You do it very efficiently.
- 게리
- 감사합니다 하느님
- Gary.
- Oh, thank you, Jesus.
가자
촌놈들이랑 놀아보자
We got to go. We're gonna
go mix with the hicks.
펄롱 의원이 전화해서
얼굴보고 얘기 좀 하잡니다
Congressman Furlong called and
he'd like some face time.
그래, 차라리 내 거시기에 불을 지르겠다
Okay, well, let's see, I'd
rather set fire to my vulva.
- 대답은 '싫어'야
- 그분은 지금 시내에서 내년 선거 때
- So that's a no.
- He's in town trying to play nice
- 좋은 인상 남기려고 노력중이에요
- 정말이야?
- for a possible Senate run in the next year or so.
- Seriously?
로저 펄롱이 노력한다고 해봤자
브란도가 애니 꼬시려는 정도야
Roger Furlong trying to play nice is
like Brando trying to play Annie.
그거 좋네, 마이크
That's a good one, Mike.
- 감사합니다
- 잠깐, 부통령님
- Thanks, ma'am.
- Wait. Ma'am?
방금 문자를 받았는데요
따님이 쓴 논문을
I just got a message here.
Something about a paper
어떤 놈이 블로그에 올렸어요
that your daughter wrote that
ended up on some guy's blog.
봐봐, 이게 바로 중국이 인터넷을 규제하는 이유야
뭐라고 하는데?
See, this is why China regulates their Internet.
What does it say?
잘 모르겠지만, 영화 강의에서
쓴 논문이에요
I don't know. Some film studies course.
A paper she wrote.
너희들 내가 1년에 65만 달러를 등록금으로
내고 있다는 건 아니?
Did you know that I'm paying 65
grand a year to that school?
딸애가 먹는 팝콘에 버터 대신
금을 둘러야 할꺼야
They had better be putting gold on
that popcorn instead of butter, right?
- 부통령님!
- 뭐야? 이런
- Oh, ma'am!
- What? Oh, no.
- 빨랑 떠야겠다
- 저도 같이 갑니다
- I'm out of here.
- I'm coming with you.
- 뭐?
- 대통령께서 "여어, 미국" 을 모니터링 하랍니다
- What?
- POTUS wants me to monitor U.S. Hey
- 제 개인 프로젝트의 하나로요
- 아, 이런 씨발같은
- as kind of my pet project.
- Oh, for fuck's sakes.
이게 네 첫 개인 프로젝트가 될꺼다
This must be the first
pet project of yours
마취제에 의존하지 않은
that didn't involve
resorting to chloroform.
글쎄요 아직 시작하는 단계잖아요
마이크
Yeah, well,
it's early days, Mike.
네가 캐서린 문제 해결할래?
Can you take care
of this Catherine business?
- 나 어디 가봐아돼
- 어디?
- I've got someplace I've got to be.
- Where?
글쎄, 아마 켄트 데이비슨와
친해질 방법을 찾은것 같다
Well, I think I might have found
a way to get to Kent Davison.
그분 어머니를 죽이고
그 살갗을 뒤집어쓰는건 엄밀히 불법이야
If you kill his mother and then dress in
her skin, that's technically illegal.
엄밀하게는
Technically.
부통령 사무실은
의욕 충만입니다
The veep's office is pumped
새 국제정책 포트폴리오 때문이죠
about the new foreign
policy portfolio, sir.
그리고 정말 흥미로운 논문을
읽었습니다
And I read this really
interesting paper
어떻게 지역성이 실제로
on how regionality
국적보다 중요한 정치적 지표가 되는가
is actually a more significant
political prism than nationality.
자네 단지 필라테스를 즐기러 온건가?
Did you just join this
Pilates studio, Mr. Egan?
네, 그럼요
편안하네요
Yeah. Yeah, you know,
it's convenient.
- 어디에 사나?
- 바로 근처요
- Where do you live?
- Nearby.
이 지역 근방요
Local to here.
듣기로는 인질 상황이 가열되었다는데
I hear the hostage situation
is really heating up.
전에 필라테스를 해 봤길 바라네
I hope you've done
Pilates before.
대부분은 이 기구들 중 아무거나
할 수 있다고 생각하는데
People think they can just
get on one of these machines.
아니, 이 기구를 사용하기까지
6개월 걸렸지
No. Six months I did
before I got on this.
네, 그래요
저도 장기적으로 보고있어요
Yeah, well, I'm all about
the long-term goals.
마이크, 이것좀 봐요
Mike, look at this.
보라니까요, 마이크
Look at this, Mike.
부통령 전용기에서 마시는 커피라
Just sipping some coffee.
Air Force Two.
진짜 좋네요
창 밖 보는 사진좀 찍어주세요
Real good. Take a picture of
me looking out the window.
조나, 조나
진정해
Jonah.
Jonah, calm down.
로고 붙어있는 비행기지
달 분화구가 아니야
It's a plane with a logo.
It's not Space Mountain.
대통령 전용기에서는 대체 어떻게 있는거냐?
자위라도 하냐?
What the hell do you do on Air Force
One, rub your dick on the seats?
사실 대통령 전용기 타본 적 없어요
I haven't actually
been on Air Force One.
- 뭐?
- 한번도 타본 적..
- What?
- I haven't been--
오!
Oh!
- 부통령님
- 으엑
- Ma'am.
- Ugh.
- 좀 어때, 마이크?
- 좋습니다
- How you doing, Mike?
- I'm doing great, ma'am.
네 재정상황에 대해서 들었어
Heard about your
financial situation.
너도 알다시피
보트랑 다른것 전부
You know, the boat
and everything.
괜찮습니다
It's fine.
할 수 있는 것 중
한 가지를 바꿨습니다
I've changed
the only thing I can--
문제에 대한 제 대응이죠
my reaction to things.
그리고 가끔은 팬티에도 신경을 써
Oh. And your boxers
occasionally, I hope.
이제는 매일 깨끗한거로 갈아입습니다
I have a fresh pair
every day now.
잘했네, 마이크
Oh, good for you, Mike.
저, 부통령님
Hey, ma'am?
왜, 게리?
무슨 일 있어?
What, Gary?
What's wrong?
저를 감수성이 풍부하다고 생각하시는건 알지만
I know you think
I'm melodramatic, ma'am.
네가 감수성이 풍부한건 알아
I know you're melodramatic.
저희 세상은 이제 끝났습니다
Uh-huh.
Our world has just ended.
마이크!
Mike!
읽어봐
Read this.
이게 뭡니까?
What is this?
"전격공개 : 부통령의 숨겨진 손짓"
Selina's
secret stash of signals.
부통령이 오른쪽 귀를 문지르면
수행비서가 그녀에게
When the VP rubs her right
ear, an aide will tell her
받아야 할 중요한 전화가 왔다고 한다
she has an important call
that she must take.
원하지 않는 대화가 있을 경우에
이것이 그녀의 탈출 전략이다
In an unwanted conversation,
this is her exit strategy."
좋아, 누군가가
위키리크스에 까발렸구만
All right, well, somebody
WikiLeaked the code.
이제 그건 사용하면 안돼
새 수신호가 필요해
So we can't use those.
We need new signals.
1년동안 사용하던건데요
Those signals took years.
수신호사전을 찢어버릴 순 없어요
I can't just tear up
the gestictionary
그리고 요런 새 신호를 생각하는것도
and come up with new codes like that.
이건 신호로 비춰질 수 있겠어요
조용한거로 생각해봐요
Okay, that could be a signal.
Kind of a silent click.
여러분 제발
그래, 우리 잠깐만
Would you please--
okay, could you just--
그냥 오늘 사용할 기본적인 신호가 필요해
I just need something
basic for today.
난 건초를 가구로 사용하는 인간들한테 붙잡혀서
I don't want to get
stuck talking pig shit
돼지똥같은 얘길 하고 싶지 않아
with people who use
hay as furniture.
난 탈출 전략이 필요해
I need an exit strategy
4시 30분까지 DC에 도착해야 한다구
생각좀 해보자
to be in DC by 4:30,
so start thinking.
좋아요, 하지만 우린 새 신호를 세밀하게 만들어서
Okay, but we have to make
these new signals subtle
신호처럼 보이지 않게 해야합니다
so they don't kind of
look like signals.
그게 옛날 신호의
You do realize that
that was the point
- 핵심이었다는건 알고있니, 마이크?
- 알고있었습니다
- of the old signals, right, Mike?
- I realize that.
아! 손바닥을 서로 비빈다음에
Oh! You slap
your hands together.
으뜸 포즈를 하는거에요
Kind of give it
a little thumbs up.
아니, 마치 벌레를 죽인다음에
No, that's like
I squished a bug
"오, 내가 벌레를 죽이다니 킹왕짱!"
하는 것 같잖아
and then I said, "Oh, it's
so cool I squished a bug."
아니면 휴대폰으로 머리를 긁는건 어때요?
What if you scratched your head
with your phone in your hand?
이건 어때?
What about this?
오, 이런..
Oh. No...
- 예뻐보이지 않으세요
- 잊어버려
- You don't look pretty.
- Oh, forget it.
생각났어요
눈썹을 문지르세요
I got it. You can
rub your eyebrow.
아무도 보지 못할꺼에요
섬세하죠
No one will see that.
It's subtle.
자연스러워 보이네
It looks natural.
사람들이 내 눈썹에 똥 묻었다고 생각하면 어떡해?
What if people think
I have crabs in my eyebrows?
어떻게 눈썹에 똥이 묻을 수 있어요?
How can you have crabs
in your eyebrow?
그래, 게리
남자랑 여자가
Okay, Gary, when a man
and a woman
정말로 서로 사랑하면
남자의 생일에..
love each other very much
and it's the man's birthday--
- 모자 안의 똥이네
- 뭐?
- Crap in a hat.
- What?
- 따님이요
- 왜? 무슨일이야?
- It's your daughter.
- What? What is it?
따님은 괜찮아요, 그런데
따님이 한 일을 보면 족치고 싶으실 껍니다
She's fine, but she's done something
that'll make you want to kill her.
염병할
안 뜬데가 없네
Christ, it's everywhere.
그냥 영화 수업 에세이잖아
Well, if it's just
a film studies essay--
아니, 캐서린의 에세이는
No, Catherine's essay is about
Emad Burnat 의 영화인 "5 Broken Cameras"
에 대한 거야
Emad Burnat's movie
"5 Broken Cameras."
오언 윌슨(배우) 영화가 아니면
모르는 영화야
If Owen Wilson's not in it,
I probably don't know it.
이건 웨스트뱅크의 이스라엘 정착촌에 대한
It's about nonviolent
Palestinian resistance
비폭력 팔레스타인 저항군 이야기야
to Israeli settlement
on the West Bank.
역시 오언 영화로는 안보이네
That doesn't sound
like one of Owen's.
캐서린은 잔인하고 불법적인 이스라엘의 침략을
She talks about
the masterly portrayal
훌륭하게 묘사했다고 적었어
of brutal, illegal
Israeli aggression.
- 한 방 먹었네
- 성명서 내야돼
- Ouch.
- We have to issue a statement.
좋아, 그래
전형적인 이스라엘과
All right, well,
standard issue pro-Israeli,
팔레스타인의 문제군
약간 이스라엘에 치중해서 쓰면 되고
pro-Palestinian, but subtly
more pro-Israeli statement.
있던거 단어 바꿔서 내면
게임 끝이지
I mean, hit F9 and print
that fucker out.
아니, 이건
별 다섯개 짜리야
No, this needs
to be top-notch.
씨발같은 무답무쟁계의
This needs to be
the Gettysburg Address
게티스버그 연설 급이 필요해
of tightrope-walking,
say-nothing bullshit.
내가 활약할 때군
My time has come.
좋아, 다음 선거때
플로리다에선 지겠네
All right, well, next election
I guess we lose Florida, then.
15분 안에 도착합니다
We got wheels down in 15.
좋아
변신해야겠군
All right, I've got to change.
알겠습니다
에이미한테 문자하죠
All right, I'll text Amy.
게리, 오늘 뭐 입을까?
Gary, what am I
supposed to wear today?
차라리 그게 낫겠네요
At least that's good.
그래, 다들 반갑구나
Well, howdy, y'all.
오, 세상에나
이것 좀 봐
Oh, my goodness.
Look at this.
계속 걸어다니며
돼지 이야기를 하네요
Walking the walk,
talking the pork.
다 큰 여자가 솜사탕 들고 있는 것 좀 보세요
Look at you, a grown
woman with cotton candy.
분홍색이 아가씨인 줄 알았네요
둘다 껴안아줄께
Pink like your cheeks. I'm
gonna give you both a hug.
오, 이런
손가락을 빨아먹을만큼 즐거워보이네요
Oh, gosh, that looks
like finger-licking fun.
오늘 만든 신조어에요
마음에 드세요?
That's a term I just coined today.
Do you like it?
모두 즐거운 시간을 보내고 있구나
그런데 이 꼬마신사는
Everybody's having such a good time.
But this young man
앞에 먹을게 없네
이걸 어쩌지?
doesn't have anything to eat.
Now why would that be?
굶주려서 죽지 않을까 걱정이네, 아가야
I hope you're not just
starving to death, sweetheart.
어떻게 할까?
네 뼈에 있는 고기를 발라먹을까
What's going on? We've got to
get some meat on your bones.
여기 있네
And there you go.
드시고 싶은거 있으면 말씀하세요
Ask and you shall receive.
왜 내가 카우보이 모자를 쓰고 있는거야?
Why am I the only one
wearing a cowboy hat?
벗을래
I'm gonna take this hat off.
아뇨, 머리스타일 망가져요
벗지 마세요
No. Hat hair, hat hair.
Please don't.
네, 부통령님은 사람들이랑
살 잘 부비고 계십니다
Yes, she's pressing
the flesh very well, sir.
그리고 여기 사람들은
살이 가득합니다
And these people
have a lot of flesh.
정치에서 피해야 할 두가지는
Two things in politics
to avoid--
중동과 가정불화야
그리고 우린 2가지가 합쳐졌지?
Middle East and family strife.
And we're combining both?
자네는 가서 딸이 사과를 하게 만들어
Now you get the daughter
to apologize.
자네한텐 내 권한이 있어
You have my authority.
그말은 즉
대통령의 권한이 있다는 뜻이지
Ergo, you have
POTUS's authority.
- 알아들었나?
- 알겠습니다
- Understood?
- Yes, sir.
지금이 60년대면
If this were the '60s,
경비대한테 딸을 쏴버리라고 했을꺼야
we could just have the National
Guard shoot the daughter.
서관입니다, 서관
잠시만 지나가겠습니다
West Wing, West Wing.
Pardon me. Coming through.
오, 안녕 꼬마야
- Oh, hi there.
- Pardon me, West Wing. Pardon me. Excuse me.
안녕, 꼬마아가씨
백악관 직원이야
Oh, hello, little girl.
Office of the president.
옆으로 비켜주겠니
고마워
Please step off to the side.
Thank you.
부통령님, 말씀드려야 사항이 있습니다
Ma'am, I have been charged
with informing you
따님인 캐서린이 지금 명백하게
that you need to get
your daughter Catherine
사과하도록 하게 하셔야 합니다
to apologize unequivocally
and immediately.
그래? 가서 똥이나 싸지 그러셔
꺽다리씨
Yeah? Well, go shit
yourself, Long Tall Sally,
내 딸은 내가 알아서 해
because I will deal
with my daughter
내 방식대로 내 교육철학대로
in my own way on my own terms.
알겠습니다
Yes, ma'am.
- 저기 엄마 오신다
- 화상연결 했어?
- Oh, here's your ma.
- Hey, you got her?
안녕 캐서린
잘 지내니?
Hi, Catherine.
How are you?
- 안녕, 엄마
- 하지마. 소름끼치잖아
- Hi, Mom.
- Stop it. Stop it. You're freaking me out.
- 하지마
- 제가 소름끼쳐요?
- Stop it.
- Freaking you out?
아니, 캐서린
네가 아니라
No, honey.
Not you, Catherine.
마이크 말야
네 화면을 자기 몸에 갖다대길래
It was Mike. He had you
on top of his body.
그래, 타이밍이 이상하네
No, that came out wrong.
- 그래, 잘 지냈어?
- 응
- Listen, how are you doing?
- I'm okay.
갑자기 주목을 많이 받았어
I'm getting a lot of attention.
- 그래
- 카우보이 모자는 왜 쓰고있어?
- Yeah.
- Why are you wearing a cowboy hat?
돼지 축제에 왔거든
I'm at a pork event.
잘 들어, 네 에세이에 대해
아무한테도 이야기하면 안돼
Listen, you can't talk
to anybody about this essay.
미디어나 기자나
아무데도
No media, no journalists
or anything.
거기 누구 있니, 우리애기?
누구니?
You have somebody there, sweetie?
Who is that?
네, 사실
제 남친이에요
Yeah, actually,
it's my boyfriend.
거짓말!
그거 신기하구나
You're kidding.
That's exciting.
이름은 라힘이고
딜카(룸메) 오빠에요
His name is Rahim.
He's Dilka's brother.
딜카 오빠라고?
Dilka's brother?
라힘이 이란 출신인게 문제에요?
What? Do you have a problem
with him being Iranian?
캐서린, 너도 알겠지만
Okay, Catherine, you know
난 인종차별주의자가 아니란다
that I am not a racist, okay?
대학시절 내 남친은
인디언 쿼터였어
My boyfriend in college
was a quarter Cherokee.
엄마, 미안해요
그런데 사과하지는 않을꺼에요
Mom, I'm sorry, but I'm
not gonna say sorry.
- 알겠죠?
- 아니, 캐서린
- Okay?
- No, Cath--
캐서린, 끊지..
좋아
Catherine, don't--
all right.
- 일 잘 돌아가는구만
- 따님이랑 대화 잘 하셨어요?
- Well, that worked perfectly.
- Good talk with Catherine?
아주 행복한 대화를 나눴지
Well, we've had
happier conversations.
마치 할아버지가 돌아가셨다고
말했을때랑 비슷하게
Like when I told her
her grandpa had died.
할아버지를 안 좋아했었군요?
Oh, she didn't like him, huh?
아니, 그런 의미가 아닌데
No, that's not what I meant.
아, 죄송합니다
저희 할아버지은 진짜 상병신이어서
Oh, sorry. It's just my
grampy, he was a real prick.
- 좋아, 마이크
- 제 말은..
- Okay, Mike.
- I mean he was--
넌 헬리콥터 타고
You need to get a chopper.
캐서린네 학교에 가있어
I want you to go
to Catherine's college.
아니, 캐서린 픽업해서
공항으로 데려와
No. You pick her up, bring her
to the air base. All right?
수건좀 가지고 말야
딸 좀 만나야겠다
Get some towels. I may need
to daughter board her.
알갔지?
Okay?
- 헬리콥터 싫어하시잖아요, 마이크
- 그래 맞아
- You hate choppers, Mike.
- I know.
내 머리가 날개에 잘릴 것 같아서
무섭단말야
I'm always afraid I'm gonna
get my head cut off.
네, 종종 일어나죠
Yeah, it happens.
이스라엘의 군대가 비 점령..
While Israel's military
non-occupation--
아니아니 존재
No, no, presence.
이스라엘의 군대가 존재..
어쩌구 저쩌구
While Israel's military
presence-- words, words, words.
사람들이랑 놀아주는것도 존나 지치네
Oh, this whole being
pleasant is fucking exhausting.
그럼요
피곤한 일이죠
Yes, sir.
It's very tiring.
이 똥덩어리들에게 뿌려줄
수분을 모두 소진한 것 같구만
I'm running out of nice juice to
spray at these shit munchers.
안녕하세요
반가워요
Hi there.
Good to see you.
우리는 또한 팔레스타인 주민들이
정착할 고향이 생기기를 바랍니다
We also desire a settled homeland
for the Palestinian people.
여기 누가 있나 봐라
Oh, look who we have here.
진저 로저스(여배우)뿐만 아니라
진저 로저스도 있네
(주 : 덴을 진저 로저스에 비유)
Not only Ginger Rogers,
but also Ginger Rogers.
멋진 농담입니다, 의원님
Nice joke construction, sir.
내 좆에 광내려고 하지 좀 마라
눈깔 4개 달린 잉여야
Stop trying to polish my dick,
you fucking four-eyed failure.
- 좋아요
- 그리고..
- Okay.
- And--
안녕, 친구들
그냥 여기 왔다가 잠깐 들렀네
Greetings, friends. We were just
in the building, so we stopped by.
여기 오셨다고요?
창문이라도 닦으러 오셨나요?
In the building? Okay. What, are you
guys washing the windows today?
- 아니면 화장실 청소?
- 위트가 넘치네, 덴
- Working on the bathrooms?
- You're quite the wit, Dan.
그럼요, 전 위트가 넘치죠
그리고 당신은..
Yeah, I am quite the wit.
And you're quite--
우린 병원에 갈꺼에요
We were just heading
to the hospital.
저희 아버지가 점점
위독해지시네요
My father's breathing
has become very bad.
오늘 밤이 고비일지도 모른데요
They think he might not
last through the night.
그리고 덴은 나랑 같이 가서
거기서 성명문을 쓰자고
And Dan needs to come with me so
we can continue the statement.
- 죄송합니다
- 아니 괜찮네, 아버지 일은 유감이야
- Apologies.
- Oh, no, not at all. I'm sorry about your dad.
- 네, 저흰 가볼께요
- 나중에 이야기를 하자고
- Okay, we should be going.
- We'll talk another time, then.
난 언제나 여기 있으니까
I got all the time
in the world.
사실 내일이면 DC를 떠나야 합니다
We do actually have to be
out of DC by tomorrow.
- 일종의 은유야
- 엄밀하게는 아닌 것 같은데요
- It's a metaphor.
- I don't think it strictly is, sir.
말 하신 형식이..
As a figure of speech--
넌 마치 불개미로 가득찬 콘돔 같이
짜증나는 새끼야
You know, you're about as annoying
as a condom filled with fire ants.
이건 좀 은유법 같냐?
How's that for
a fucking metaphor?
- 그건 직유법이죠
- 좀 닥칠래, 돼지년아
- That's a simile, sir.
- Shut your mouth, you fat girl.
아버지는 어느 병원에 계시는데?
So what hospital
is your dad in?
조지 워싱턴
George Washington.
아, 좋은 병원이지
Oh, that's a good one.
거기엔 큰 스타벅스가 있어
They got a big Starbucks there.
꽤 멋져
그거 알아? 거기 가는 사람들 중에..
It's nice. You know, people
go in there that aren't--
- 나한테 말 걸 필요 없어
- 고마워
- You don't have to speak.
- Thank you.
여기 오셨네요, 부통령님
한번 드셔보세요
There you go, ma'am.
You taste that.
- 천국의 맛이에요
- 이거 크네요
- That's heaven right there.
- This is big.
하지만 전 다 먹을 수 있어요
But I bet I can finish it.
I-4 회랑(중앙 플로리다 지역)을
박살내야 합니다
I want to smash
the I-4 corridor--
박살낸다는건
내부 상황에 초점이 맞춰질때
and I mean smash it-- all the while
focusing on the inside game.
그렇게 되면..
이런 젠장
Then what-- holy cow.
돼지
A pig.
헬리콥터 안에서
일어난다는건 아니야
It's not being
in the helicopter.
난 괜찮아
헬리콥터 탈 수 있어
That's fine. I can
ride in a helicopter.
그냥 거기 타면
흔들리는게 무서운거야
It's just getting in.
I'm afraid it's gonna wobble.
내 머리뚜껑을 썰어버리지 않을까
Like, you know, it'd chop
the top of my head off
반숙 계란처럼 말야
like a soft-boiled egg
and then I'm, like,
돌아다니다가 내 뒤통수를
running around trying
to put my head back on.
미친짓거리에요, 마이크
전 영화 보고 감상문 쓴 것 밖에 없어요
This is crazy, Mike. All I did
was write a review of a movie.
나도 알아, 캐서린. 그런데
중동 문제는 매우 혼란스럽단다
I know, Catherine, but the whole
Middle East thing is very confusing.
그렇지, 라힘?
Right, Rahim?
아뇨, 가끔 저는 그게
뚜렷한 문제로 보여요
No, sometimes it can seem
pretty clear-cut to me.
그래, 뭐..
잠깐만
Yeah, well-- excuse me.
마이크, 자네 어디있나?
Mike, where are you?
돼지 축제에 있죠
I'm at the hog roast.
자네 목 아래부터
기능을 상실했나?
And are you paralyzed
from the neck down?
- 왜 멈추게 하질 않는건가?
- 멈춘다라..
- Why aren't you stopping this?
- Stopping...
정부의 입장이 바뀐겁니까?
Has the position of this
administration changed
이스라엘과 팔레스타인에 대해서요?
toward Israel and Palestine?
우리는 이스라엘을 지지합니다
당연히..
We support the state
of Israel, of course...
마이크, 부통령님이
돌아가는 돼지 앞에서
Mike, the VP
is voicing solidarity
유대인에게 연대를 표명하고 있어
with the Jewish people
in front of rotating pork.
- ...유대인들을 위해
- 비쥬얼 좀 바꿔봐
- ...for the Jewish people.
- Change the visual.
- 아니 치워버려
- 네 알겠습니다
- Deport the visual.
- Yes, sir.
J-1-1
J-1-1.
조나에게 긴급상황이 무엇인가요?
What's your Jonah emergency?
조나, 부통령님을 돼지한테서 치워버려
Jonah, move the veep
away from the pig.
이 장소의 민감성을 생각해봐
Think about
the sensitivities here.
뭐가요, 돼지?
이 나라 유대인들은 돼지고기 먹어요
What, pork? Mike, most Jews in
this country are fine with pork.
돼지고기 짱짱
그렇게 자주 말하죠
Pork schmork, they often say.
이 나라의 유대인들은
Most Jews in this country
돼지고기를 먹습니다. 전략관님
돼지고기 짱짱, 정말요
are fine with pork, Mr. Davison.
Pork schmork, really.
자네 구약 성경은 읽어봤나?
You ever hear of
the Old Testament, Mike?
이스라엘이랑 유럽
Israel, Europe.
조나, 이스라엘이랑 유럽이래
Jonah, Israel, Europe.
알았어요
존나 알겠으니까
Okay. Fuck.
Fine, Mike.
하지만 저한테 존나 빚진거에요
실례합니다
But you fucking owe me for this.
Excuse me.
이 돼지놈들이 부통령님께
중동 문제 물어보진 않겠지?
These pork folks won't ask Selina
about Middle East politics, right?
아, 안돼
저 병신놈들은 아마
Oh, no. Those fuckers
probably think
중동이 캔자스(미국 중부)
인줄 알껄
the Middle East means Kansas.
저기, 난 정말로 병이나
Hey, you know what? I'm not
really great with illness
죽음같은 기본적인 공감에
익숙하지 않아
or death or basic empathy,
하지만 네 아버지 일은 안됐다고
말해주고 싶어
but I just want to say
I'm sorry about your dad
그리고 넌 정말 용감한 것 같아
and I think you're
being really brave.
왜?
왜 여기서 멈추는데?
What?
Why are we stopping here?
우리 아버지셔
That's my dad.
망할, 죽어가는 것 처럼 안보이네
Jesus, he doesn't look
like he's dying.
우리 가족은 내가 좆같은 죄책감에
시달리고 있다고 생각해
My family was guilt-tripping
the shit out of me
그래서 여기 와서 그런 척 연기해야돼
and so I exaggerated
to come visit.
게다가 위독하신 아버지는
특별 사면 카드가 될 수 있지
Besides, a dying dad can be
a get-out-of-jail-free card.
- 펄롱 감옥한테서 말야
- 와우
- Like with Furlong.
- Wow.
존나 쿨하네
That is cold.
오히려 핫한건가
Also kind of hot.
...그리고 유태인들의 고향에 대해서
...and as a homeland
for the Jewish people
우리는 동시에 지원할 것입니다
while at the same time
we support
팔레스타인 주민들이 정착할 고향과
함께 말입니다
a settled homeland
for the Palestinians.
아직도 돼지 궁뎅이가 보여
I can still see the pig's ass.
다 가린게 아니야
수그려
You're not blocking it.
Bend down.
신발끈을 묶던지
뭐라도 해
Tie your shoe, whatever.
원을 사각형으로 만들기는
까다롭습니다
That's a circle
that's tricky to square.
대통령님과 저는..
And the president and I...
이 상황에선 살집있는 놈이
필요한데 말이지
We really need a bulkier man
in this situation.
- 이정도면 돼요?
- 앞으로 좀 더 가
- Am I there?
- Get closer towards it.
좋아요, 마이크
숯불 바로 옆이에요
Okay, Mike, it's right
next to the coals.
존나 뜨겁다고요
The coals are hot.
이봐요
돼지 좀 그만 만져요
Hey, quit touching the pig.
여긴 좆같은 동물원이 아니에요
It's not a fucking petting zoo.
보안 문제입니다
아시겠어요?
Ma'am, this is a matter
of security, okay?
이 돼지가 부통령님을
공격할꺼라고 생각하는거요?
You think this pig
is gonna attack her?
저 털도 없는 통구이가?
Son, that fucker
is skinned and roasted.
엄청나게 불리하다고
He's at a huge disadvantage.
보세요, 백악관 직원입니다
전 여기 있을껍니다
Okay, look, office of the president.
So I'm staying.
장례 행렬이 있다고 해도
그 거리를 사용할겁니다
I don't care if there is a funeral
procession due to use that street.
오늘 4시에 막아주세요
It is to be closed
by 4:00 today.
그게 유족을 격려할껍니다
다들 행렬을 사랑하죠
It'll cheer the family up, sir.
Everyone loves a motorcade.
안녕하세요
무슨일로 오셨나요?
Hello.
What do you want?
처리해드리지 못합니다
안녕히가세요
You can't have it.
Good-bye.
의원님께서 요 몇일 내에
The congressman
would like to have
부통령님과 아주 공손하게
대화를 나누고 싶어하셔
a very polite chat in the next few
days with the vice president.
아니, 할 수 없으셔
No, he cannot.
난 부통령님께
I need you to let the veep know
요전의 이상한 행동에 대해
사과드리고 싶어
that I just wanted to apologize
for any erratic behavior
아마 목격자가 있으실 테니까
she might have witnessed
from me in the past.
그 이상한 행동이라는게
의원님이 사무실로 쳐들어와서
Does erratic behavior include
you storming into this office
모두한테 깽판친
그 일이라는거죠?
and violently yelling
at everyone?
그래, 그땐 내가 내가 아니었어
Yes.
I wasn't myself.
돌아버릴만한 사정이 있었지
I was having a bit
of a rough go.
내 마누라가..
이걸로 날 동정하지는 말고..
My wife-- and I'm not looking
for sympathy for this--
신장질환으로 매우 아팠어
but she was very ill
with kidney disease.
의원님 부인은 꿩강하신데요
시에틀 마라톤에도 참석했고
Your wife is perfectly fine.
She ran the Seattle Marathon.
그래, 이제 엿 좀 그만 먹여
All right, don't fuck
with me, honey.
그냥 스케쥴러에
내 좆같은 이름을 쳐 넣으란 말야
Just put my fucking name
in your stupid fucking schedule
그리고 당장 부통령님 얼굴을 보게 해!
and get me a face-to-face
with the veep now!
죄송합니다
지금 나가셔야겠는데요
Excuse me. You need to leave
this office now, sir.
- 나가셔야 합니다
- 아, 정말?
- We do need to leave.
- Oh, really?
좋아, 설리나 마이어는
나한테 존나 따먹힐 줄 알아
Okay, I've got boxes
and boxes on Selina Meyer.
알아들었어?
You understand me?
존나 홍콩행 티켓을 끊어주지
I've got Pandora's
fucking boxes on her.
하지만 우리는 당신 정당의
많은 거짓말과 싸우고 있는걸요
But we're fighting the lies
from many people in your party
축산업이 환경에 미치는 영향이라던가
about the environmental
impact of what we do.
폐수 없이 돼지를 기르는건 불가능합니다
You can't raise pigs
without excrement, ma'am.
- 그렇군
- 그건 안 될 일입니다
- Uh-huh.
- It just can't be done.
- 네, 알아들었어요
- 깨끗합니다
- I see. Yes.
- They defecate.
그리고 빨리 깨끗해지죠
And they defecate with speed.
- 어머 세상에
- 양도 그렇고요
- Oh, Lord. Oh, goodness.
- And volume.
글쎄요, 기억할께요
저 돼지들
Well, I hear that.
They're pigs.
왜 그렇게 규제하는거야?
전 다른 사람들과도 얘기를 나눠야겠어요
Why wouldn't they? And I'm interested
to hear a few other folks.
시간 내 주셔서 감사합니다
안녕, 미스 아메리카?
- I thank you for your time. Hello, Miss America?
- Yeah.
내가 3시간 반동안 지랄같이
눈썹을 긁어댔는데
I've been scratching my eyebrow for
three and a half fucking hours.
- 대체 어디 있었어?
- 눈썹 긁기는 안 하는거 아니었어요?
- Where have you been?
- I thought we weren't doing the eyebrow thing.
- 똥같다면서요
- 좋아, 지금부터 눈썹긁기 사용할꺼야
- You said about the crabs.
- Okay, from now on, we're doing the eyebrow thing.
알갔지?
우린 여기서 나가야돼
Okay? And we've got
to get out of here.
제 여친이 눈썹긁기 생각해낸거라고
말 안했죠?
Did I tell you my girlfriend
came up with the eyebrow thing?
오, 그래, 잘했네
이제 갈꺼야, 알았지?
Oh, well, good for her.
We've got to go, right?
중간선거 이후로
종말이 찾아온 것 같아요
Since the midterms,
it's been really apocalyptic.
- 너 바쁜건 잘 안다
- 괜찮아
- We know you're busy, hon.
- It's fine.
하지만 전 지금 아빠한테만
집중하고 있어요
But right now I am focused
on you, Daddy.
쟤가 덴 이건 이야?
Is that Dan Egan?
그러니까 우리 수신호를
여친이랑 상의했단 말이지?
So you discussed our signals
with your girlfriend?
네, 창의적이죠
Yeah, she's really creative.
제 생각엔 다른 좋은 것들도
생각해낼 것 같아요
I thought she could come
up with some good ones.
그리고 그녀가 그걸 알고 있는
유일한 민간인이라는거지?
And is she the only civilian
that you shared them with?
- 네, 부통령님
- 으흠
- Oh, yes, ma'am.
- Uh-huh.
그게, 아니.. 음
데이나는 유출하지 않을껍니다
Well, no-- oh, no.
Dana would not leak.
- 전형적인 첫 단계, 부정하기
- 조용히해
- Classic first-stage denial.
- Quiet.
내 말은, 맞는 것 같아
게리, 생각해봐
I mean, it must be.
Gary, think about it.
분명 데이나야
It must be Dana.
오 세상에
Oh, my God.
입이 싼 여자일세
She's getting her leak on.
너랑 같이 살고있는 염병할 냄새는 뭐니?
What in the living fuck is
that god-awful smell, Jonah?
아, 제 자켓에 약간 돼지기름이 묻었습니다
Oh, my jacket is partially
soaked in pork fat, ma'am.
아
Oh.
그럼 너희 둘이 같이 돌아가서
그 다음엔?
So you two aren't
back together, then?
아뇨, 그냥 직장동료입니다
No, no.
Just colleagues.
- 자네 에이미에게 상처를 줬네
- 아니에요
- You broke her heart. You know that?
- No.
- 아냐 맞아
- 아니. 덴은..
- Yeah. Yes.
- No. He--
손도 안잡더라
우린 3번이나 데이트 했었어
he didn't even graze it.
We went on three dates.
망할 에이미
포기가 빠르네
Oh, dang, Amy.
You put out quick.
에이미랑 저는 사귈 수 없어요
Amy and I just weren't
compatible.
그래, 나랑 비슷한 일을 하는 사람이랑
사귈 수 없다는걸 증명했지
Right. It turns out I can't mate
with anyone outside of my species.
우린 네가 필요한게 뭔지 알아, 에이미
We all know what you need, Amy.
비난하려는건 아니야
I mean besides a big, fat slap.
전 자식이 필요하지 않아요
I do not want children, okay?
왜 아무도 이해를 못해요?
Why can nobody accept this?
지금 당장 결정하라는게 아니야
Sweetie, you do not
have to decide right now.
아직 시간이 많잖니
You still have plenty of time.
- 나는 56살까지 임신이 가능했단다
- 굉장하시네요
- I remained fertile till I was 56.
- Terrific.
- 그냥 내가 보지를 달고 있다고..
- 제발, 에이미
- Just because I have a vagina...
- For God's sake, Amy.
우린 네가 행복해졌으면 하는거야
We just want you
to be happy, sweetie.
전 자식 없이도 행복해요
I am happy without kids.
- 정말로.. 알아요?
- 말도안되게 행복합니다
- I am-- right?
- Oh, she's deliriously happy.
다들 활기찬 에이미라고 부르죠
At work we actually
call her Amiable Amy.
커피 뽑으려고 하는데
누구 필요한 사람?
I think I'm gonna go get a coffee.
Anyone else?
- 난 괜찮다
- 커피 나르는거 도와줄게
- No, thank you.
- I will help you carry that second coffee.
난 정말 중요한 영화에 대한
에세이를 쓴거야
I wrote an essay about
a very important film.
오히려 날 자랑스러워 해야돼
Okay? You should
be proud of me.
*"다마스커스에 간 데비" 가 아니라고
(주 : 영화 Debbie Does Dallas)
It's not
"Debbie Does Damascus."
물론 네가 자랑스럽단다
하지만, 딸아
No, I am proud of you.
But, sweetheart,
우리가 이스라엘계의
표심을 잃는다면
if we lose
the pro-Israel vote,
2년 후에 플로리다에서 질꺼고
then we lose Florida
in two years
29명 선거인단이니
and that's 29 electoral votes.
그럼 엄마는 실직자가 되는거야
And then Mommy's out of a job.
좋아, 그래도 난 사과 안할꺼야
Okay, I'm still
not going to apologize.
내가 말하는 영화 보기는 했어?
Have you even seen the movie
that I'm talking about?
엄마가 영화 볼 시간이 어디있니?
When would I have time
to see a film?
엄마는 아직도
I haven't even been able to see
파란 인간들이 나오는
아름다운 영화도 못봤어
that wonderful movie
with the blue people in it.
- "아바타" 말이죠
- 그래 "아바타"
- "Avatar."
- "Avatar." Exactly.
그래, 졸업하려면 얼마나 남았니?
1년?
So you graduate
in what, a year?
네 그러길 바래요
남은 두 학기 동안
Yeah, hopefully, if I can
get the money together
등록금을 낼 수 있다면요
for the last two semesters.
쪼들리는구나, 그치?
Ah, money's tight, huh?
들어봐, 내가 돈을 대하는 마음가짐은..
You know, my attitude
to money is--
22살에 졸업을 하고나면
빚이 6만 달러에요
I'll be 22 when I graduate,
I'll owe 60 grand.
그리고 계산을 해보니
제 학자금 융자는
And I did the math.
I'll chase my student debt
향후 27년간
저를 따라다닐 예정이에요
for the next 27 years
of my life.
저기, 커피 있는데
마실래?
Hey, fresh coffee back here
if you guys want some.
아, 좋아요
Oh, great.
Yeah.
커피좀요
Coffee.
아, 젠장
젠장맞을
Oh, God.
Oh, my God.
내 빚이 10만 달러인데
I owe 100 grand.
좆망이네
Sweet Jesus Christ.
엄마도 영화 보고 싶어
그리고 볼 꺼야
I want to see the film
and I will see the film.
게리, 영화 찾아놔
"Five Easy Pieces"
Gary, we need to get it.
It's "Five Easy Pieces."
"5 Broken Cameras" 에요
It's "5 Broken Cameras."
- 그래 "Broken Cameras"
- 엄마, 더 이상 괴롭히지 마
- Okay, it's "Broken Cameras."
- Mom, don't even bother.
이건 "수퍼사이즈 미" 같은 짓이야
This is gonna be like "Super
Size Me" all over again.
가서 "맘마미아!"나 다시 보지 그러세요
Why don't you guys just
go see "Mamma Mia!" again
존나 10번째 보는 거겠네요
for the 10th fucking time?
욕하지 마라, 캐서린
하지마
Do not swear at me, Catherine.
Don't.
응, 알았어
잘못했어
Okay, look, I'm sorry.
네가 얼마나 상처받았는지
이해한단다
I understand that you
are feeling attacked, babe.
그게 엄마가 지금 여기 있는 이유야
And that's why I'm here
with you right now.
국제안보회의도 제끼고 왔어
I'm supposed to be
at a national security meeting,
- 하지만 네가 나의 최우선이잖니?
- 응
- but you are my priority, okay?
- Okay.
- 무슨 말 하는지 알지?
- 응, 사과할게
- You hear what I'm saying?
- Yeah, I'll apologize.
- 착한 딸내미네
- 추수감사절을 라힘네 가족들이랑 보낼 수 있다면
- Good girl.
- If I can spend Thanksgiving with Rahim and his family.
아니, 얘야
할머니가 오실텐데
No, darling.
We've got Grandma coming.
할머니한테 웃으면서
푸딩을 잘라드려야지
We got to smile at her
and cut her Jell-O.
그래, 수?
Yeah, Sue?
마이크, 아직 통조림에 갇혀계시면
얼른 끄집어내세요
Mike, if she's in the can,
haul her out.
종이처럼 납작해져도
상관 없으니까
I don't care
if she's trailing paper.
지금 출발하셔야
제시간에 도착합니다
She can make this if she
leaves right this second.
따님이랑 얘기중이야
She's currently
with her daughter.
잘 들어요 마이크
남자답게 우선순위를 매기세요
Look, Mike, man up
and prioritize, okay?
저는 매일 하는 일이죠
우선순위
I do it every day.
Prioritize, that is.
알았어
Okay.
- 수요일은 어때?
- What about Wednesday?
- Ahem.
부통령님, 뱀처럼 스스륵
비행기에 타실 시간입니다
Ma'am, you need to make like a
snake and get on that airplane.
그래, 하지만 난 지금
Okay, but I'm in the middle
내 딸과 중요한 이야기 중인걸
of an important conversation
with my daughter.
- 모든 일정은 연기해, 알았지?
- 알겠습니다
- So everything can be put on hold, okay?
- Okay.
- 고마워
- 당연하지
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
그럼 난 엄마랑 할머니랑
추수감사절을 보내겠네
So I have to spend Thanksgiving
with you and Memaw.
- 그래
- 수요일에
- Yes.
- Wednesday.
수요일은 아빠랑이야
Wednesday you're with your dad.
목요일은 나랑 할머니고
Thursday you're
with me and Grandma.
금요일은 새 남자친구랑
알았지?
Friday you can be with
the new boyfriend, okay?
토요일도
And Saturday.
토요일 저녁에는 집에 온다면
If you come home
on Saturday night.
알았어, 라힘이랑 얘기해볼께
Yeah, I'll check that
over with Rahim.
좋아, 이제 갑시다
Okay, let's get going.
- 훌륭한 협상가세요
- 나도 알아
- You are a great negotiator.
- I know I am.
수한테 전화왔는데
Hey.
So Sue called.
확실하게 펄롱 의원한테
한 방 먹였데
Apparently she
bitch-slapped Furlong.
수한테 밥 한번 사야겠네
He usually has to pay for that.
당장 캐서린 사과문 작성해야해
And we need that
Catherine apology ASAP.
알겠지? 넌 여기에 있어
Okay? I can do it,
you can stay here.
이메일로 연락할게
We'll liaise
via e-mail.
음, 그게
난 정말..
Um, yeah.
I really--
사실, 그거 알아?
난 네가
Actually, you know what?
I would prefer it
물리적으로 같이 있는게
더 좋아
if you were physically there.
중요한 성명서를 작성할때는 말야
It's, you know,
an important statement.
네 말이 맞아, 뭔 일이 생길 지 모르니까
가자
You're right. It needs to happen.
Let's go.
천만의 말씀
You're welcome.
활기찬 에이미라고?
그게 최선입니까?
Amiable Amy? That is the
best you could come up with?
그래, 차라리
"에이미 화이트하우스" 라고 할 껄 그랬어
Yeah, you know, I knew I should
have gone with Amy Whitehouse.
만나뵙게 되서 영광입니다
It's very nice meeting you...
- 나도 만나서 반가워
- 부통령 각하
- It's so nice to meet you, too.
- Madam Vice President.
그래, 전공이 뭔가?
Sure. What are you
studying at school?
컴퓨터과학이요
수학 부전공에
Computer science.
Math minor.
장래희망은?
Where are you headed
with all that?
희망사항이지만
정부 기관에서 일하고 싶습니다
Hopefully, actually,
get into a government branch.
- 국방부나 FBI나
- 그래그래
- Defense or FBI, maybe.
- Uh-huh.
- 글쎄요, 페르시아어를 할 줄..
- 페르시아어도 할 줄 알아?
- Well, I speak Farsi--
- You speak Farsi?
- 네
- 여기서 태어났지?
- Yeah.
- But you were born here?
- 네, 여기서 태어났습니다
- 그래, 좋아
- Yes, I was born here.
- Uh-huh, great.
부모님도 여기서 태어나셨니?
And your parents
were born here?
아뇨, 부모님은
이란 테헤란 출신이세요
They were actually
born in Iran in Tehran.
네, 거기에서 제 가족들이 왔죠
Yeah, that's where we're from.
- 그래, 알겠어. 테헤란이군
- 넵
- Oh, I see. Tehran.
- Yeah. Yep.
국방부의 머셔 장군 전화입니다
Ma'am, General Mercer from the
Pentagon is on the phone.
아, 지금은 전화받을 상황이 아니야
Oh, I don't need to talk
to General Mercer right now.
- 급한 전화에요
- 아니 장군 전화같은건 필요 없다고
- He's pretty insistent.
- I don't need a General Mercer call right now.
진짜 전화에요
He's really on the phone.
- 머셔 장군 전화라고
- 네네
- Oh, General Mercer's on the phone.
- Mm-hmm.
2초만 기다려줄래?
Can you hang tight
two seconds, Rahim?
- 머셔 장군님
- 갑자기 전화드려서 죄송합니다
- General Mercer.
- I'm sorry to be calling, Madam Vice President,
하지만 25분정도
but we are going
to be discussing
인질에 대해 토의할 예정입니다
the hostage situation
in around 25 minutes.
여기서 같이 얘기하시겠어요
아니면 우리끼리 할까요?
Do you think you can get here or
should we go ahead without you?
아니아니아니
나 빼놓고 얘기하지 말아요
No, no, no. Don't go
ahead without me.
- 비행기에 화상 연결할꺼에요
- 제가 할께요
- We can set up a video link from the plane.
- I'm on it. I got it.
완벽하게 작동할 껍니다
So that would
work out perfectly.
그리고 라힘 좀 붙잡아놔
And I want Rahim to stay.
I've got to-- mm-hmm.
- 라힘, 여기있으렴
- 네, 좋아요
- Rahim, stay. You, too, Catherine.
- Yeah, okay.
- 감사합니다. 부통령님
- 고마워요
- Thank you, Madam Vice President.
- Thank you.
우리 정말로 가봐야 할 것 같아
We should actually probably go.
중간고사 공부해야돼
I have to get back
to study for a midterm.
그래그래
부모님 성함은?
Yeah, yeah. What are
your parents' names?
- 라힘은 멋진 청년이라는게 증명됐고
- 그렇습니다
- That Rahim turns out to be a nice boy.
- Yes, ma'am.
그의 가족에 대해 보안 조사를 실시해줘
Let's run a security check
on him and his entire family.
알겠습니다
Yes, ma'am.
- 재무 조사도 병행해서
- 알겠습니다
- And investigate their finances.
- Yes, ma'am.
제 재정상태에 대해
다시 생각해보았는데요
I was actually reconsidering
my financial situation.
오, 나한테 돈 달라고 하는거야?
Oh, are you about to ask me
for money, Mike?
- 저도 그런 말 하기 싫어요
- 아냐아냐아냐
- I don't want to.
- No, no, no.
네가 그럴꺼라고 생각했고
나도 너한테 돈 주고 싶어
I thought you would and I
want to give you money.
그리고 나 돈 있어
안될건 또 뭐람?
And I have the money, so why not?
사실
그건 그렇게 큰..
Exactly.
And it's not a big--
내 공보수석에게 돈을 준다라..
Giving cash to my director
of communications--
잘 먹힐 꺼라고 생각해?
do you think that that
would play well, Mike?
- 그럼요
- 아니, 아니. 효과 없어
- Yeah.
- No. No, it wouldn't.
제발요
No, ma'am.
이런식으론 화상 회의 못해
I can't videoconference
like this.
머리가 이렇게 눌렸는데
I can't get
the dent out at all.
- 삐에로 같잖아
- 고쳐드릴까요?
- I look like Bozo.
- Do you want me to fix it?
- 드라이기 가져왔어?
- 못하겠네요
- Oh, do you have a blow-dryer?
- I don't.
아니, 모자는 누가 쓰자고 한거야?
No. Whose idea
was this hat?
- 그것도 데이나 아이디어야?
- 끄덕끄덕
- Was that Dana's idea, too?
- Mm-mm.
- 걔한테 말했어?
- 문자했어요
- Did you talk to her?
- We texted.
- 그리고?
- 데이나가..
- And?
- She--
수신호 얘기를
she may have mentioned
the signals
- 친구한테 했데요
- 어휴
to one of her girlfriends.
화상회의 연결했습니다
The link to your video
conference is up, ma'am.
게리야..
Gary...
이런 말 하기 싫지만
I do not like to say this,
오늘 날 정말로 실망시키는구나
but you have truly
disappointed me today.
날 좆되게 만드는 새로운 아이디어 또 없니?
Do you have any idea how
foolish you have made me look?
명심할께요
I do.
오늘은 최고의 날이에요
I am having the best day.
이렇게 행복할수가
This is such a great time.
부통령 전용기도 타고
"여어, 미국" 작전도 성공했어요
We're on Air Force Two.
U.S. Hey is getting started.
우리가 플로리다 표심을 잡았어요
Guys, we saved
the Florida vote.
아이패드 스크래블 해봤어요?
You guys want to play
iPad Scrabble?
조나, 제발
닥쳐라
Jonah, please.
Just shut up.
마이크
Mike, you want to...
제 자켓에 묻은
돼지기름좀 핥아볼래요?
suck some of the pork fat
out of my jacket?
이리와요
공짜 점심
Come on, it's a free meal.
로리, 켄트 데이비슨 아직도 여기 다녀?
Hey, Lori. Does Kent
Davison still come here?
아뇨, 안다니세요
No, he left.
여기에 DC 사람들이 너무 많이 온다나
He said it was too full
of DC people or something.
나 어제 네가 "*플레이북" 에 대해 언급한걸 들었어
(주: 블랙베리 태블릿)
I see you got a mention
in "Playbook" yesterday.
- 그래
- 멋져
- Yep.
- Awesome.
나 구글 알림에 네 이름 설정해놨어
I have a Google alert
set up for your name.
- 오우
- Krauthammer(유명 언론인)가
- Wow.
- Hey, did you catch Krauthammer
포스트지에 쓴 인질 사건 기사는 봤어?
in the "Post" about
the hostage situation?
네가 주차장에서
나한테 매일 인사하는 놈이냐?
Are you the guy that always
says hi to me in the garage?
응
Yeah.
그래, 가서 웨이트나 해야지
Yeah, I got to do
some fucking weights.
이건 병신짓이야
This is for rubber idiots.